<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kevin egbert</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 15:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abstractions in PureData</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is to easily explain how to use abstractions in Pure Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstractions and sub-patches will make it easier to compartmentalize a complex patch and break it down into smaller parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An abstraction is a Pd patch that can be used as an object in another Pd patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create an abstraction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a Pd patch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save the patch in specificed location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call an instance of that object in your new patch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The abstraction must be saved in a place where Pd can find it. If you navigate to Pd-extended &amp;gt; Preferences, you can see a list of paths that Pure Data is searching through. You can either specify a new path or use one of the paths listed here. For Mac users recommend using Users/username/Library/Pd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://at.or.at/hans/pd/objects.html&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 02:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pd-abstraction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pd-abstraction</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Isometric Projection Studies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/iso1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/iso2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/iso3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 02:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/isometric</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/isometric</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Relative Noise, Dancing Glass</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;home&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glass.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


I completed my senior thesis on communication noise and its effects on mediated communication in part to acquire my BA in New Media @ SUNY Purchase. &lt;a href=&quot;http://kevinegbert.com/Relative_Noise.pdf&quot;&gt;You can read it here.&lt;/a&gt; The photos below are of the accompanying exhibition. I find windows and glass beautiful and that's only part of the reason why I choose to work with them as sound generating and sculpting material. I think that glass, a flat and invisible channel that is often less the focus then the light it lets in, acts as an ideal material to begin talking about communication channels and as a metaphor for different media forms.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The audio piece below is a segment of the composition accompanying the installation. Sound source material was recorded using contact mics attached to glass window frames that would pick up rain and the passerby. The sound was then played back through the frames using transducers in the gallery space.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;css/styles.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/346349234&amp;amp;color=%23ff9900&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=false&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;masonry&quot;&gt;
&lt;!-- image 1 --&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com&quot;&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glass1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- image 2 --&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com&quot;&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/edit3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com&quot;&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/edit4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com&quot;&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glass.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com&quot;&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/party.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/body&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 02:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/glass</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/glass</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come Have Coffee With Us</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/203753288&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;link href=&quot;/css/styles.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

&lt;body&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
“A special monastery where they had two abbots seats, one occupied by the actual abbot, and the other always empty. New monks that came to the monastery grew curious as to why it was empty, and after some time, they would ask. In fact the second teacher of the monastery was an important entity that had there for a longer time than any other monk. The third seat was reserved for the relationship between all of the monks and practitioners of the monastery.”
&lt;p&gt;When you sit down to drink coffee with someone, there is usually two chairs. One for you, and one for the other person. Really, there is you, there is me, and the relationship born between us. There is my self concerns, and your self concerns. There is my wishes as to how you see me, and you have these wishes too. In addition, there is something invisible, which is why the seat is empty. The relationship between us has its own needs, requirements that are different from the two individuals. We don’t often think about the relationship formed. We look at ourselves, we look at the other person, but not the relationship itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;I openly invited some strangers to have coffee with me and our relationship, regardless of if we had one to date. Just like everyone has self interests, desires, and needs, there is a third entity that needs to be nurtured. That is, the relationship between us.
When we recognize that we not only need to care for ourselves and those close to us, that we need to care for the relationships we build with others, we begin to treat ourselves and others with more respect. We begin to listen with the intent to understand rather than to reply. We begin to make stronger relationships, one where there is three parties, not two.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 02:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/coffee</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/coffee</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Immersive Birdwatching</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;home&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Immersive Birdwatching&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a project that opens up conversation surrounding wearable technology that is supposed to empower the user to continue their research hands free. The dysfunctional interface brings into question our attempts at creating interfaces that enable us to further our research and extend our experiences with the natural environment and our human relationships to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headpiece utilizes two shotgun microphones interfaced with a handheld audio recorder. The microphones are placed at ear distance apart to create three dimensional stereo audio recordings. Binoculars are attached to a beer drinking helmet that allows for hands free magnification. Hot glued leaves conceal you when you need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/birdwatching3.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;img/blue.png&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;link href=&quot;css/styles.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;masonry&quot;&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/birdwatching2.gif&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/birdwatching1.gif&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/birdwatching4.gif&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/birdwatching5.gif&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/img/ib1.png&quot;&gt; --&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/297569453&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;h1&gt;currently.&lt;/h1&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;h2&gt;Empowering each other.&lt;/h2&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;h3&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- [resume](http://kevinegbert.com/resume.pdf) --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 13:28:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Immersive-Birdwatching</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Immersive-Birdwatching</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BAM Digital Arts Studio 1/2</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;home&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late July I volunteered at the Brooklyn Academy of Music, assisting with a summer digital media and electronics camp for elementary students.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Digital Arts Studio ran from July 18th to July 22nd and worked with students ranging from the age of eight to nine. The second session ran from the 25th to the 29th and worked with students from ages ten to eleven.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
BAM, which is located in downtown Brooklyn, has been open and operating since 1908. The academy is known for is progressive and avant garde performances. While also operating as a large scale performance center, BAM has focused on urban arts and community needs, including workshops and classes for students.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Students worked on group as well as individual projects ranging from building drawing robots to creating sound maps. The maps were made out of common craft materials but interfaced with a Makey-makey controller, allowing users to touch specific locations on the map and trigger audio of field recordings that students recorded during a walk through downtown Brooklyn.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Digital Arts Studio at BAM was in partnership with The School for Poetic Computation, an artist-led school for beginners and professionals exploring the creative use of software, hardware, and theory.

&lt;!-- In partnership with The School for Poetic Computation in collaboration with Molmol Kuo

Like paint or words, electronics and source code can be used as tools to create new works of art and poetry. This truly inventive workshop expands students’ understanding of the artistic process by demonstrating how electronics can be integrated into art. Activities include learning the basics of electricity, incorporate drawing and code, build a handmade computer, and create an audio landscape of the BAM neighborhood with noise and sound.

PARTICIPANTS WILL:
• Develop abstract reasoning skills
• Develop logical thinking and analytical research
• Understand the principles of code and abstraction --&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;css/styles.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;masonry&quot;&gt;
&lt;!-- image 1 --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- image 2 --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;!-- &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bam7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!--
We went for a soundwalk.

Here is a map.

Here are some recordings that we made

IMAGES. --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 02:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/BAM-sound-walk</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/BAM-sound-walk</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rye 3/11/16</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/251595004&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 01:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rye</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rye</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>pi / arduino / pD audio effects processor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/149586351&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project uses Raspberry Pi, Arduino, and PureData to create a digital multi-fx &quot;pedal&quot; to process sound in real time. The tutorial covers setup with the pi to both PureData and Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end goal is to use PureData (a visual programming language developed for creating multimedia works) to manipulate audio in real time with the help of a usb audio interface. PureData can be easily installed on a Pi and through some setup, an Arduino can be used to control parameters in the PureData patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main focus of this tutorial is to share my path in integrating PD to run “headlessly” on the Raspberry Pi. Despite a more extensive setup with the pi, the lack of computer peripherals and components opens up many opportunities in creating interactive systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will jump right into using a USB audio interface with the pi and move into configuring it with pureData. If you still need to setup your pi, you can check out my extensive posts below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;pDuino&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pDuino is an object created by Hans Christoph Steiner. It handles communication between Arduino microcontrollers and the PureData software. This is important to us because it allows us to integrate electronic components like knobs and switches that can change parameters in our Pd patch. This is what allows us to construct a physical device that can control our patch dynamically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to visit:
http://at.or.at/hans/pd/objects.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download the pDuino object and Firmata firmware.
Firmata is what will be loaded onto the Arduino and allows PureData complete control in terms of turning on digital and analog inputs on the Arduino board.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extract the pDuino archive to a known location on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a path in PureData to the archive location so that PureData can reference it and create arduino objects.
This is done by going to preferences – path – new. You should browse to the folder and apply the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More documentation here: http://en.flossmanuals.net/pure-data/ch060_installing-pduino/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Using a USB Audio Interface with Rasberry Pi and PureData&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a USB Audio Interface with the pi and using alsamixer to record/play audio from command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some USB interfaces are compatible with the pi. In my case I am using an Audiobox USB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using alsamixer will allow you to select your sound card instead of the default hdmi.
to record a file called “rectest” into the current directory…​arecord -D plughw:0 –duration=10 -f cd -vv ~/rectest.wav​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to play it back (using the soundcards output)…
aplay -D plughw:0 ~/rectest.wav&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​The 0 after plughw: refers to my interface. It was listed as 0 as you can see here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alsa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing and Configuring PureData with the pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether sharing internet from ethernet or just plugging right in to your router, install PureData. Note: This will only install PD-Vanilla. To use the Arduino controller we will have to install other packages. This will be discussed later…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install puredata&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vnc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see in the image above that I am VNCed into my pi and accessing PureData through the gui. Once PD is done installing it will be listed under the sound and video menu on the pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to preferences in PD and make sure your usb interface is selected as audio input/output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pd_audio_settings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running PD “headless” on the pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get patches running on the pi with no need for monitor/keyboard/mouse there are two things that must be accomplished. The first thing is that you need to create a script that tells the pi to open the Pd patch on start up and the second is handled in the Pd patch itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cron jobs are perfect for having Pd patches run at startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that is complete, you need to add the following string into PD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will delay the patch from loading immediately which is required in order for it to run properly on startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other tip…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is what the post that helped me looked like…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[loadbang]
|
[delay 100]
|
[; pd dsp 1(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 01:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pi-arduino-audio-processor</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pi-arduino-audio-processor</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>just like you imagined</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Super 8 film manipulated with circuit bent analog video hardware. Post-processing done using digital editing software.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/148065304&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 15:04:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/just-like-you-imagined</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/just-like-you-imagined</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>limbo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...an uncertain period of awaiting a decision or resolution; an intermediate state or condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/limbo.gif&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 23:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/limbo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/limbo</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
